https://www.fiscalnote.com/privacy/

Skip to Main Content
FiscalNote
Main Navigation
Solutions
All the solutions you need, all from the #1 most trusted provider.
FiscalNote
Manage your issues, stakeholders and team’s efficiency in one powerful platform
CQ Federal
Unlock precision bill alerts, summaries, analysis, transcripts, floor video and more - as it happens
FiscalNote State
Monitor and report on key state legislature and regulatory information in seconds
FiscalNote Global
Monitor global policy with our issues management solution
EU Issue Tracker
Track legislation and review analysis from our experts in Brussels
Political Moneyline
Track donations and analyze the flow of money pouring into PACs, candidates and 527s
NEWS, MEDIA & ANALYSIS
CQ News
Glean actionable policy insights from the most trusted newsroom on the Hill
Roll Call
Access non-partisan coverage of the people and politics of Capitol Hill
FiscalNote Markets
Get best-on-the-Street analysis and data to identify opportunity and mitigate risk
Congressional Directories
Get your hands on Congress At Your Fingertips®, the definitive Congressional directory
ADVOCACY & GRASSROOTS ENGAGEMENT
VoterVoice
Launch advocacy campaigns to amplify your message with lawmakers in minutes
Knowlegis
Find and contact the right members and staffers for those all-important meetings with lawmakers
Converge
Create and launch a custom, mobile advocacy experience
Advocate Acquisition
Scale up your advocacy supporters where and when you need them with an easy-to-use digital solution
PACbuilder
Keep your PAC on track with a centralized system for managing donations
ADDITIONAL SERVICES
Professional Services
Customize your policy efforts with the help of our team
Advertising
Educate the most influential people in Washington with results-driven ad campaigns
FiscalNote Accelerate
Find, apply and get alerted to funding programs across the U.S.
The 2021 State Legislative Sessions Calendar
Keep track of key dates in the 2021 state legislative sessions calendar across all 50 states and Washington, D.C. in one place with this free and handy download.
Featured
The Biggest Issues Facing State Legislators in 2021
The pandemic will pare 2021 state priorities to mitigation and economic recovery. A look at the top issues on legislative agendas next year.
Related Links
Blog
Case Studies
Whitepapers
On-Demand Webinars
Upcoming Webinars
Webinars
About
More than 4,000 organizations trust our solutions to manage their most important policy issues.
Related Links
Our Company
From people, to policy, to politics, FiscalNote is on a mission to reinvent the way organizations around the world understand the bigger picture.
Our Newsroom
Get insights from experienced experts about how policy developments will likely play out and impact you.
Careers
Join a company that values fierce curiosity and radical innovation.
Your Security
Discover why FiscalNote is the #1 most secure solution.
Find Your Legislator
Quickly identify and contact your elected officials.
Request Demo
Sign In
1. General
1.1. FiscalNote, Inc., and its group companies (“FiscalNote”) respects your online privacy and security and protects information that you decide to share with us, in an appropriate and reasonable manner. Your privacy and the protection of data is our top concern and we have established and comply with the principles set forth in this FiscalNote Privacy and Security Policy in order to protect your privacy and your data. FiscalNote does not list all of the details of the FiscalNote infrastructure for security reasons.
1.2. Your access to, license and use of FiscalNote’s web-based Services (the “Services”) is strictly conditioned upon your agreement with and consent to the terms and conditions of the FiscalNote Privacy and Security Policy, as it may be amended and/or updated from time to time by FiscalNote. In the event of any material change or modification by FiscalNote to the FiscalNote Privacy and Security Policy, FiscalNote will notify you here. You also agree to comply with all of the terms and conditions of the FiscalNote Terms of Service Agreement and our Cookie Policy.
1.3. FiscalNote performs the roles of a data controller and data processor during the course of its business. As a data controller, we determine the purposes and manner in which personal data is processed. As a data processor we process personal data on behalf of a customer.
2. Contact Information
2.1. Please direct all inquiries, questions or comments with respect to this FiscalNote Privacy and Security Policy to FiscalNote at the email addresses set forth below. FiscalNote will use commercially reasonable efforts to respond to your inquiries, questions or comments within five (5) business days of their receipt.
Privacy Email Address: privacy@FiscalNote.comSecurity Email Address: security@FiscalNote.com
Should you reside in the European economic area, please contact us at the following Email Address: EUprivacy@FiscalNote.com
3. Information Included in Our Service and How it is Used
In order to provide the Services, we may collect and process information about public officials from publicly-available sources, such as government websites, a public official’s individual website, and other similar resources. The information we gather may include name and contact information of such officials. This information is used as part of summaries or compilations of data related to legislative and regulatory activity to provide our customers with a tool by which they can gain and understanding of legislation, regulations and their status, as well as the methods for contacting public officials.
4. Information Collected About Users of Our Public Websites and How it is Used
In order to access certain Services, you may be required to provide information about yourself (such as identification or contact details) as part of the registration process for the Service, or as part of your continued use of the Services. We use this information to provide you with information about our products and services and to contact you about important updates to our Services.
5. Information Collected About Users of Our Permission-Based Service and How it is Used
Our customers may provide information to us about their permissioned users, and for whom we maintain separate accounts on our Service. When they do so, we serve as a data processor that process the information that they provide us on their behalf.
6. Your Responsibilities when Using our Service and our Websites
When you use our Services, you agree to abide by certain rules of conduct, including the following:
6.1. You agree that any registration information you give to FiscalNote will always be accurate, correct and up to date.
6.2. You agree to use the Services only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the Terms of Service Agreement and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions (including any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the United States or other relevant countries).
6.3. You agree not to access (or attempt to access) any of the Services by any means other than through the interface that is provided by FiscalNote, unless you have been specifically allowed to do so in a separate agreement with FiscalNote. You specifically agree not to access (or attempt to access) any of the Services through any automated means (including use of scripts or web crawlers) and shall ensure that you comply with the instructions set out in any robots.txt file present on the Services.
6.4. You agree that you will not engage in any activity that interferes with or disrupts the Services (or the servers and networks which are connected to the Services).
6.5. Unless you have been specifically permitted to do so in a separate agreement with FiscalNote, you agree that you will not reproduce, duplicate, copy, sell, trade or resell the Services for any purpose.
6.6. You agree that you are solely responsible for (and that FiscalNote has no responsibility to you or to any third party for) any breach of your obligations under the Terms of Service Agreement and for the consequences (including any loss or damage which FiscalNote may suffer) of any such breach.
7. Your Passwords and Account Security
7.1. You agree and understand that you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of passwords associated with any account you use to access the Services.
7.2. Accordingly, you agree that you will be solely responsible to FiscalNote for all activities that occur under your account.
7.3. If you become aware of any unauthorized use of your password or of your account, you agree to notify FiscalNote immediately.
8. Contents of Your Account
8.1. FiscalNote stores and maintains certain forms and contents stored in your account; however you are responsible for ensuring that you have sufficient rights to include the contents in your account.
8.2. In order to prevent loss of data due to errors or system failures, we also keep backup copies of data including the contents of your account and such contents may remain on our Services even after deletion or termination of your account; however, we are committed to retaining personal data for only as long as needed, taking into consideration customer requirements, legal retention requirements, and operational or other similar audit requirements.
9. Visitor Details
We may use the Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, referring URL, files accessed, errors generated, time zone, operating system and other visitor details collected in our log files to analyze the trends, administer the website, track visitor’s movements and to improve our website.
10. Cookies
10.1. We may use session and/or persistent cookies with respect to the FiscalNote Services. We may also, from time to time, retain an independent third party to perform an analysis of the statistical and aggregate data and other information with respect to our Services. Such aggregated information is not personally identifiable and is used to improve the functionality and/or use of our Services and future product offerings.
10.2. Such third parties may, at their option, employ the use of cookies in the provision of their third party services. FiscalNote does not have access to these third party cookies nor are we responsible for them.
For more information about our use of cookies, please see our “Cookie Policy.”
11. Your Obligations
11.1. You have certain obligations imposed by applicable law or regulations or by the FiscalNote Terms of Service Agreement. You must, at all times, respect the terms and conditions of this FiscalNote Privacy and Security Policy, including but not limited to any intellectual property rights, which may belong to third parties. You must not disseminate, distribute and/or download any information which may be deemed to be injurious, offensive, violent or racist.
11.2. Any violation of these obligations and guidelines in the FiscalNote Terms of Service Agreement or in the FiscalNote Privacy and Security Policy may lead to the termination or suspension of your access to or license of the Services by FiscalNote, at its sole option.
12. Children
Individuals under 18 are not eligible to use FiscalNote’s Services. Moreover, FiscalNote does not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under 18. If you are under 18, you should not use our service. If you become aware that we inadvertently hold or have access to personal data about anyone under 18, please let us know so we can delete it.
13. Forums / Chat / Blogs / Directory
13.1. If you choose to use a bulletin board or directory, import a blog, or participate in a chat room, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information or personal data you choose to provide there can be read, collected and/or used by other parties and that such personally identifiable information could be used to send you unsolicited messages.
13.2. FISCALNOTE IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION OR PERSONAL DATA THAT YOU CHOOSE TO SUBMIT WITH RESPECT TO THESE FORUMS.
14. Surveys and Polls
14.1. As a licensed user with respect to FiscalNote Services, you may receive requests from time to time to participate in market research, including but not limited to certain polls and surveys which may be submitted by independent third parties retained by FiscalNote for market research. Any personal data collected by a third party will be subject to privacy policy of that third party.
14.2. If you decide to participate in such surveys or polls, you acknowledge that you are responsible for the provision of any and all of your personal and/or other information in response to such poll or survey.
15. Legal Disclaimer
IT IS POSSIBLE THAT WE MAY NEED TO DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION WHEN REQUIRED BY LAW, SUCH AS RESPONSES TO CIVIL OR CRIMINAL SUBPOENAS, OR OTHER REQUESTS BY LAW ENFORCEMENT PERSONNEL. WE WILL DISCLOSE SUCH INFORMATION IN THE EVENT THAT WE HAVE A GOOD-FAITH AND REASONABLE BELIEF THAT IT IS NECESSARY TO COMPLY WITH A COURT ORDER, JUDICIAL PROCEEDING, SUBPOENA, OR OTHER LEGAL PROCESS OR REQUEST TO FISCALNOTE BROUGHT IN ANY COUNTRY THROUGHOUT THE WORLD, OR TO EXERCISE OUR LEGAL RIGHTS OR DEFEND AGAINST LEGAL CLAIMS.
16. Accessing and Changing Your Account Information
16.1. You can review the personal information that you have provided to us and make any desired changes to such information by logging in to your account on the FiscalNote website.
16.2. Please be aware that even after we have processed your request for such a change, FiscalNote may retain certain residual information in the backup and/or archival copies of FiscalNote’s database.
17. Closing Your Account
FiscalNote may retain certain data contributed or provided by you if we reasonably believe that it may be necessary to prevent fraud or abuse; it is retained for legitimate business purposes (such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data for account recovery purposes); or, if it is required by law.
18. Data Rights
18.1. If you are located in the European economic area, you have certain rights under European law with respect to your personal data, including the right to request access to, correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your personal data. If you wish to exercise these rights, please contact EUprivacy@FiscalNote.com. You may also have the right to lodge a complaint with the applicable supervisory authority in the member state of your residence. If you are an account holder that was permissioned by a customer, please contact the customer directly as we serve as a processor on their behalf, and can only forward your request to them to allow them to respond.
18.2. Additionally, if you are located in the European economic area, we note that we are generally processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you register to receive a report from our website), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above, unless we are required by law to obtain your consent for a particular processing operation.
19. International Transfers
We may transfer some of your information to the United States in order to provide our Services. Because the United States does not have equivalent data protection legislation protecting the use of your personal information, we comply with European Union law by using Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission or by adopting other means to ensure that adequate safeguards are applied.
20. Links from FiscalNote Website
20.1. Certain pages of our website may, from time to time, contain external links. You should verify and validate any and all privacy practices of other websites. We encourage you not to provide personal information, without first assuring yourself of the privacy policies of such other websites.
20.2. FISCALNOTE IS NOT RESPONSIBLE IN ANY WAY FOR ANY USE AND/OR MISUSE OF ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION OR OTHER INFORMATION PROVIDED BY YOU AT SUCH OTHER WEBSITES.
21. Anonymous Data
21.1. FiscalNote may accumulate and aggregate certain anonymous statistical and related data in order to improve the performance and functionality of its Services, to develop new products and/or Services or to analyze the usage of FiscalNote’s Services.
21.2. FiscalNote may use aggregated anonymous data for such purposes as FiscalNote, in its sole discretion, deems to be appropriate.
22. Security
22.1. Access to personal information and/or your data at FiscalNote is password-protected and PCI compliant. FiscalNote may use a credit card processing company with respect to the billing of Services fees and such third parties may use such personally identifiable information solely to provide such billing services. FiscalNote also audits its system, from time to time, for possible vulnerabilities.
22.2. It is your responsibility to protect the security of any of your login information. Emails, instant messaging and other similar methods of communication may not be encrypted, and we urge you not to use these means or methodologies for the communication of any confidential information.
23. FiscalNote Employees
23.1. FiscalNote’s employees have years of experience in managing and assessing security and data protection risk. Only FiscalNote employees with the highest level of clearance have access to our datacenter and the data contained therein. FiscalNote limits access to customer data to only a designated number of its employees with a legitimate need to access such data in order to provide technical, support and other important services for FiscalNote’s customers.
23.2. FiscalNote, on a continuing basis, reviews its then current security policies and develops new policies and/or procedures with respect to management, knowledge sharing, escalation procedures and day-to-day operations. FiscalNote routinely and regularly audits its security policies and procedures and those same policies and procedures are regularly reviewed by FiscalNote executive management.
23.3. Any access to customer data is solely on an as needed basis by authorized FiscalNote employees or by FiscalNote senior management employees in order to provide and perform maintenance and/or support services for our customers, and in order to maintain or improve the quality of our Services.
24. FiscalNote Network Security
24.1. FiscalNote’s network security system and infrastructure helps to protect our customers’ data against sophisticated attacks. FiscalNote uses intrusion detection systems to protect and screen its services. Access to the FiscalNote network is tightly and comprehensively controlled and strictly audited by appropriate FiscalNote personnel.
24.2. Communications between a customer’s computer and FiscalNote’s servers is encrypted and FiscalNote applications operate in a secure operating system that FiscalNote believes minimizes vulnerabilities.
25. Redundancy
25.1. In a cloud computing environment, certain computer resources may at some point fail to operate – FiscalNote has designed its infrastructure in light of that potential failure. The core cloud computing infrastructure provides redundancy and high availability at every level, from multiple Tier-1 ISP connections, redundant networking equipment, and servers.
25.2. FiscalNote’s Services are built on this infrastructure with the ability to quickly add or change service capacity in response to customer load or in an uncommon situation where a compute infrastructure experiences a failure.
25.3. FiscalNote monitors each of its Services critical performance metrics to track availability and performance.
23.4. FiscalNote periodically backs up appropriate data across multiple servers so as to protect that same data in the event of a service failure.
26. Physical Security
FiscalNote Services are hosted in secure, SAS70 Type II certified facilities that are protected from physical attacks and from natural disasters. Such datacenters are monitored on a 7×24 basis and entrance to the datacenters is controlled and restricted to a select group of authorized personnel. Multiple forms of authentication must be used in order to enter any such datacenter and the datacenters are guarded and protected 7 days a week, 24 hours a day.
27. EXCLUSION OF WARRANTIES
27.1. NOTHING IN THESE TERMS SHALL EXCLUDE OR LIMIT FISCALNOTE’S WARRANTY OR LIABILITY FOR LOSSES WHICH MAY NOT BE LAWFULLY EXCLUDED OR LIMITED BY APPLICABLE LAW. SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF CERTAIN WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OR THE LIMITATION OR EXCLUSION OF LIABILITY FOR LOSS OR DAMAGE CAUSED BY NEGLIGENCE, BREACH OF CONTRACT OR BREACH OF IMPLIED TERMS, OR INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES. ACCORDINGLY, ONLY THE LIMITATIONS WHICH ARE LAWFUL IN YOUR JURISDICTION WILL APPLY TO YOU AND OUR LIABILITY WILL BE LIMITED TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW.
27.2. YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK AND THAT THE SERVICES ARE PROVIDED “AS IS” AND “AS AVAILABLE.”
27.3. IN PARTICULAR, FISCALNOTE, ITS SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS DO NOT REPRESENT OR WARRANT TO YOU THAT:
(A) YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES WILL MEET YOUR REQUIREMENTS,
(B) YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, TIMELY, SECURE OR FREE FROM ERROR,
(C) ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED BY YOU AS A RESULT OF YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES WILL BE ACCURATE OR RELIABLE, AND
(D) THAT DEFECTS IN THE OPERATION OR FUNCTIONALITY OF ANY SOFTWARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS PART OF THE SERVICES WILL BE CORRECTED.
27.4. ANY MATERIAL DOWNLOADED OR OTHERWISE OBTAINED THROUGH THE USE OF THE SERVICES IS DONE AT YOUR OWN DISCRETION AND RISK AND THAT YOU WILL BE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER SYSTEM OR OTHER DEVICE OR LOSS OF DATA THAT RESULTS FROM THE DOWNLOAD OF ANY SUCH MATERIAL.
27.5. NO ADVICE OR INFORMATION, WHETHER ORAL OR WRITTEN, OBTAINED BY YOU FROM FISCALNOTE OR THROUGH OR FROM THE SERVICES SHALL CREATE ANY WARRANTY NOT EXPRESSLY STATED IN THE TERMS.
27.6. FISCALNOTE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.
28. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY
28.1. YOU EXPRESSLY UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT FISCALNOTE, ITS SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES, AND ITS LICENSORS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR:
(A) ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL CONSEQUENTIAL OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, HOWEVER CAUSED AND UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY. THIS SHALL INCLUDE, BUT NOT BE LIMITED TO, ANY LOSS OF PROFIT (WHETHER INCURRED DIRECTLY OR INDIRECTLY), ANY LOSS OF GOODWILL OR BUSINESS REPUTATION, ANY LOSS OF DATA SUFFERED, COST OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES, OR OTHER INTANGIBLE LOSS;
(B) ANY LOSS OR DAMAGE THAT MAY BE INCURRED BY YOU, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OR DAMAGE AS A RESULT OF:
(I) ANY RELIANCE PLACED BY YOU ON THE COMPLETENESS, ACCURACY OR EXISTENCE OF ANY ADVERTISING, OR AS A RESULT OF ANY RELATIONSHIP OR TRANSACTION BETWEEN YOU AND ANY ADVERTISER OR SPONSOR WHOSE ADVERTISING APPEARS ON THE SERVICES;
(II) ANY CHANGES WHICH FISCALNOTE MAY MAKE TO THE SERVICES, OR FOR ANY PERMANENT OR TEMPORARY CESSATION IN THE PROVISION OF THE SERVICES (OR ANY FEATURES WITHIN THE SERVICES);
(III) THE DELETION OF, CORRUPTION OF, OR FAILURE TO STORE, ANY CONTENT AND OTHER COMMUNICATIONS DATA MAINTAINED OR TRANSMITTED BY OR THROUGH YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES;
(III) YOUR FAILURE TO PROVIDE FISCALNOTE WITH ACCURATE ACCOUNT INFORMATION;
(IV) YOUR FAILURE TO KEEP YOUR PASSWORD OR ACCOUNT DETAILS SECURE AND CONFIDENTIAL;
OR
(V) YOUR FINANCIAL OR BUSINESS DECISIONS BASED ON THE CONTENT PROVIDED.
28.2. THE LIMITATIONS ON FISCALNOTE’S LIABILITY TO YOU SHALL APPLY WHETHER OR NOT FISCALNOTE HAS BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF ANY SUCH LOSSES ARISING.
FAIR PROCESSING NOTICE FOR EUROPEAN PUBLIC OFFICIALS
Last date of revision: December 12, 20191.	WHAT IS COVERED BY THIS FAIR PROCESSING NOTICE
1.1.	In order to provide its services, FiscalNote Inc. ("FiscalNote" or "We") collects and processes personal data of European public officials ("public officials" or "you") from publicly-available sources (e.g. the EU Parliament website, government websites, a public official's individual website etc.). It concerns both Members of the European Parliament (MEPs) and national legislators (i.e. French, German, Russian, Swiss, Ukrainian or UK legislators).
This information is used on our FiscalNote platform ("the platform") which can be used by our customers to gain understanding of legislation, regulations and their status, as well as the methods for contacting public officials.
1.2.	It is our top concern to protect your privacy and to process your personal data in a fair and transparent manner. This Fair Processing Notice explains how and why we process your personal data, how we protect them and how long we keep them.
For more general information about why and how we process personal data when we perform our business activities, please read our Privacy Policy.
1.3.	Please follow the links below for further information:
Who will process your personal data?What is the purposes for processing your personal data? What are the legal grounds for processing your personal data? What are your rights with respect to the processing of your personal data? Which categories of personal data will be processed? Who will have access to your personal data? Will your personal data be transferred to countries outside the EEA? Will we make use of automated decision-making? How long will your personal data be retained? Are your data safe and secure? Who can you contact? Changes to this Fair Processing Notice?
2.	WHO WILL PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA
2.1.	FiscalNote, with offices at 1201 Penssylvania Avenue NW, 6th Fl. Washington D.C. 20004, determines the purposes and means of the processing of your personal data in the context of the platform.
Consequently, we act as a separate controller with respect to these data.
3.	WHAT ARE THE PURPOSES FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
3.1.	We only process your personal data for legitimate business purposes. These purposes include but are not limited to:
-	the good organisation of our services;
-	feeding the platform with relevant information regarding European public officials to provide our clients with a useful tool;
-	keeping the information regarding European public officials on the platform accurate and up to date.
4.	WHAT ARE THE LEGAL GROUNDS FOR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
4.1.	In the context of the platform, we will process your personal data because it is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests, more specifically the good organisation of our services by providing our clients with an accurate and up to date platform.
4.2.	Before relying on legitimate interests, we always assess whether our interests are not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights and freedoms. For the processing of your personal data, we have conducted a so-called "Legitimate Interests Assessment" (LIA) and we have concluded that legitimate interests is an appropriate basis for processing. Upon request, you can obtain more information on the LIA and its outcome.
5.	WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS WITH RESPECT TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
5.1.	You have several rights concerning the information we hold about you. We would like to inform you that you have the right to:
•	obtain confirmation that we are processing your personal data and request a copy of the personal data we hold about you;
•	ask that we update the personal data we hold about you, or correct such personal data that you think is incorrect or incomplete;
•	ask that we delete personal data that we hold about you, or restrict the way in which we use such personal data if you believe that there is no (longer a) lawful ground for us to process it;
•	object to the processing of your personal data, as this is based on legitimate interests as a legal basis, in which case we will cease the processing unless we have compelling legitimate grounds for the processing.
5.2.	If a valid request is received, all conditions are met and no exemption applies, we will take every reasonable step to comply with your request (e.g. by removing all personal data from our databases if it concerns an erasure request). Please note however that, because of the technical mechanisms that are available to us, it may be impossible to comply with your request entirely, due to backups, the organization of third-party data etc. More specifically, it may be impossible for us to completely remove personal data from publicly available sources (e.g. the EU Parliament website, government websites, a public official's individual website, and other similar resources) because of the way the platform is organized.
If it would be technically impossible to comply entirely with your request, we will inform you about this.
5.3.	In order to exercise any of your rights, you can send us a request, indicating the right you wish to exercise by e-mailing us at EUprivacy@FiscalNote.com.
5.4.	If you are unhappy with the way we have handled your personal data or any privacy query or request that you have raised with us, you have a right to complain to the Data Protection Authority (“DPA”) in your jurisdiction.
All national DPA's can be found here: list national DPA's.
6.	WHICH CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA WILL BE PROCESSED?
6.1.	The following categories of personal data are processed in the context of the platform:
•	Information processed from Members of the European Parliament: name, EU Party, nationality, national party, date of birth, place of birth, Brussels office address, Strasbourg office address, postal address, email, phone number, fax number, website, Facebook address, Twitter address, Committees and delegations;
•	Information processed from national legislators (i.e. French, German, Russian, Swiss, Ukrainan or UK legislators): country, party, chamber, district, sessions in Office, Twitter, website, Facebook.
The platform does not contain supplementary information beyond what is listed.
6.2.	We obtain these data from publicly-available sources (e.g. the EU Parliament website, government websites, a public official's individual website, and other similar resources).
7.	WHO WILL HAVE ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
7.1.	Employees and representatives of FiscalNote who are responsible for the platform will have access to the information on the platform and this on a strict need-to-know basis.
7.2.	The users of the FiscalNote platform will have access to this information too. These users have committed themselves:
•	to use the platform only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the Terms of Service Agreement and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions;
•	not to access (or attempt to access) the platform by any means other than through the interface provided by FiscalNote, unless they are specifically allowed to do so in a separate agreement;
•	not to engage in any activity that interferes with or disrupts the platform (or the servers and networks connected to the platform);
•	not to reproduce, duplicate, copy, sell, trade or resell the (information on the) platform for any purpose, unless they are specifically allowed to do so in a separate agreement;
7.3.	Furthermore, we may disclose your personal data to affiliated companies, third parties that provide services to us that reasonably require access to personal data relating to you for one or more of the purposes mentioned above.
7.4.	We also reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on us.
8.	WILL YOUR PERSONAL DATA BE TRANSFERRED TO COUNTRIES OUTSIDE THE European economic area?
We may transfer some of your information to the United States in order to provide our Services. We have adopted Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission (art. 46 GDPR) as appropriate safeguard to ensure compliance with data protection requirements.
If you need any clarification about your personal data being shared to the United States, please contact EUprivacy@FiscalNote.com.
9.	How long will your personal data be retained?
9.1.	Your personal data will not be retained longer than necessary for the purposes described above.
9.2.	As a general rule, your data will be deleted immediately if they are not relevant anymore for the platform (e.g. when the information is outdated because you are not a MEP or a national legislator anymore, because the data are not accurate anymore etc.).
10.	ARE YOUR DATA SAFE AND SECURE?
10.1.	FiscalNote employs strict technical and organizational (security) measures to protect the information in the platform from access by unauthorized persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage.
These measures include:
Training to relevant staff to ensure they are aware of our privacy obligations when handling personal data and disciplinary action in the event of non-compliance
Immediate deletion of data if not relevant anymore (e.g. because the information is outdated);
Commitment of the users of the platform:
-	to use the platform only for purposes that are permitted by (a) the Terms of Service Agreement and (b) any applicable law, regulation or generally accepted practices or guidelines in the relevant jurisdictions;
-	not to access (or attempt to access) the platform by any means other than through the interface provided by FiscalNote, unless they are specifically allowed to do so in a separate agreement;
-	not to engage in any activity that interferes with or disrupts the platform (or the servers and networks connected to the platform);
-	not to reproduce, duplicate, copy, sell, trade or resell the (information on the) platform for any purpose, unless they are specifically allowed to do so in a separate agreement;
•	Termination or suspension of the access to or license of the platform in case of a violation of the FiscalNote Terms of Service Agreement and/or the Security Policy;
•	Password protection and access control by appropriate FiscalNote personnel;
•	Network security and intrusion detection systems
to protect the platform against sophisticated attacked and to minimize vulnerabilities;
•	Cloud computing infrastructure which provides redundancy and high availability at every level, from multiple Tier-
ISP connections, redundant networking equipment and servers;
•	Hosting of the platform in secure SAS70 Type II certified facilities that are protected from physical attacks and from natural disasters. The datacenters are monitored on a 7x24 basis and entrance to the datacenters is controlled and restricted to a select group of authorized personnel. Multiple forms of authentication must be used in order to enter any such datacenters.
•	Security incident management;
•	Recovery, contingency and emergency plan.
11.	Will we make use of Automated Decision-making?
11.1.	Automated decisions are defined as decisions about individuals that are based solely on the automated processing of data and that produce legal effects that significantly affect the individuals involved.
11.2.	As a rule, your personal data will not be used for automated decision-making. We do not base any decisions about you solely on automated processing of your personal data.
12.	WHO CAN YOU CONTACT?
12.1.	We hope that this Fair Processing Notice helps you understand, and feel more confident about, the way we process your data. If you have any further queries about this notice, please contact EUprivacy@FiscalNote.com.
13.	CHANGES TO this FAIR PROCESSING NOTICE
13.1.	We may modify or amend this Fair Processing Notice from time to time. To let you know when we make changes to this notice, we will amend the revision date at the top of this page. The new modified or amended notice will apply from that revision date. Please check back periodically to see changes and additions.
California Privacy Rights
Last Date of Revision: Jan 30, 2020.
1. The California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA), effective January 1, 2020, gives California consumers enhanced rights with respect to their personal information that is collected by businesses.  First, California consumers may opt out of having their personal information sold to other persons or parties. Second, they have a right to know:
1.     What specific pieces of information a business has about the consumer;
2.     Categories of personal information it has collected about the consumer;
3.     Categories of sources from which the personal information is collected;
4.     Categories of personal information that the business sold or disclosed for a business purpose about the consumer;
5.     Categories of third parties to whom the personal information was sold or disclosed for a business purpose; and
6.     The business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling personal information.
In addition, California consumers can request that the personal information a business has collected about them be deleted from the business’s systems and records.
FiscalNote may be considered a covered business under the CCPA as it collects and processes the personal information of California consumers. This Privacy Policy provides the required notices to California consumers.  The CCPA also prohibits covered businesses from providing discriminatory treatment to California consumers if they exercise their rights under the Act.
FiscalNote does not presently sell any personal information to third parties for any purpose.
To make a "request to know" or "request to delete" your personal information, send us an e-mail at privacy@FiscalNote.com (Please put either “Request to Know” or "Request to Delete" in the subject heading of your email.)  You may also submit these requests via an online form (available at this link).
We will honor these requests for US individuals whether or not you are a California consumer under the CCPA.
We will confirm receipt of your request within 10 days along with a description of what steps we will take to verify and respond. We must provide the requested information or delete your personal information within 45 days of receipt of your request. If necessary we can take up to an additional 45 days, but we must let you know the additional time is needed.
When contacting us, we may ask you to provide certain, limited personal information, such as your name, email address and/or account login ID and/or password, to verify your request and to match with our records and systems. This is also to protect against fraud. We will not retain this personal information or use it for any other purpose.  Also please be advised that we need to search our records and systems only for the preceding 12 months.
Residents of other states may also have similar rights to request information about or delete their personal information.  To inquire about exercising these rights, please contact us at privacy@FiscalNote.com.
2. Pursuant to California’s "Shine The Light law" (California Civil Code § 1798.983), California residents are entitled, once a year and free of charge, to request the disclosure of certain categories of personal information to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year, if any.  Under the law, a business should either provide California customers certain information upon request or permit California customers to opt out of this type of sharing.
You may request this information by contacting us at privacy@FiscalNote.com and indicate in the email subject line, "California Shine The Light Request."  Please include your mailing address, state of residence and email address with your request.
3. Currently, our systems do not recognize browser-based "do-not-track" requests.
last updated: 6/17/2020
